Mark 17, 2020, six, and we're out of the
indication from the Deacon and all
things, just for church, Mr. Perry,
Susan, what is it?
How about the vicar instead of the Deacon?
The vicar?
Oh, my God.
That's okay.
Well, okay, it was supposed to be here.
Okay, it was supposed to be here.
All right, so let us pray.
Almighty God, you give us new life, new hope,
and new opportunities with each day.
Help us to use these blessings to the best of
our abilities in doing the work before us,
devoting ourselves to your service,
and putting our own interests aside
to seek the welfare of our community.
Direct us a Lord in all our doings,
with your most gracious favor,
and further us with your continual help,
that in all our work begun, continued, and ended in you.
We may glorify your name.
In Jesus' name, we pray, amen.
Amen.
I pray to you to the flag of the United States, Mary.
And to the throne of the Republic of the States,
one of my nation and a man out in the world
with a good opportunity, just as oral.
Number four, public input, unscheduled personal appearances,
have none.
Five, eight claims list.
We're super, sorry.
Local, gyms, fat, bar, high, perfect.
Five, five, five.
Five, B claims list for Vance, auto group.
Motion book, please, sir.
Local, tight.
Estep, bar, gyms, high, bar, high, perfect.
Epstein.
Five, C, Gdell, Stratton, Edmunds,
and Palmer Claiming for the Pinsicola,
D.R. D.A., relaxing thing in the amount of $315.
So this is, like you said,
this claim is for $315, just finishing up
all the documents, I think, for the settlement, and everything.
If it's approved, we will have our main balance
at $577,000, $460, and $0.40.
So this will be our last claim from Gdell Stratton.
I think there might be one more, but I mean,
I'm sure the board's feeling for the board, sir.
Okay.
On this civil litigation, there's all the checks
been distributed yet, but we know where that's at.
We have a target date when all the checks will be distributed.
I was told, April.
By the end of April.
That's how I took it.
Motion approved.
So I took it.
Jen, back.
Foreign, E-FET.
All right.
Done, Paul.
Hi.
Harper.
Back.
By D, Tetra Tech claim for the Pinsicola Gd.A.
We're licensing them out $13,150.
This is for Tetra Tech, you know,
they're engineered on this process.
They've been doing a lot of modeling and different things.
Like that.
If this is approved,
it'll literally run around about that.
five hundred seventy a thousand four hundred sixty dollars in forty cents.
Five hundred sixty dollars in forty cents.
Five hundred.
I have a couple.
Hi.
Thank you.
A minute's from the marks third twenty twenty six of regular meeting.
Most two approved.
Do.
I have the same.
Don't want to.
Do you have a couple?
All right.
Five hundred fifty dollars.
five hundred fifty dollars.
Five.
not to see $338,1008 and authorized the trust manager to sign the contract
contingent bond of all legal review and Oklahoma Water Resources Board approval.
And there.
Good evening.
This will be a water line that will go from our new water tower just south of
that and go across the interstate and feed the east side of the turnpike it'll be
really good deal because we only have currently we only have one feed of water that
goes to that side so we'll be able to feed the water to go around there on that
side.
I'm going to be good for any kind of expansion that we have to do so.
Yep.
Is this to a hundred thirty eight thousand modern eight part of the grant funds?
If we haven't yet left it we're going to use it so it's kind of the way we said
without our people.
So if we didn't have any left is this something we budgeted for?
Yes sir.
Question number.
Second.
Five.
Four per per per per per per per per per.
Hi.
There.
Stand up here.
Five.
G.
War bid to border states for the MSU A 25-85 fiber material project and authorized the trust
manager.
negotiate contract.
Consistent with the bid documents you'd tend to upon legal review and confirmation of
funding availability both bitter and MSU A recognized that many of the units to be provided
under the bed.
between bitter and MSUA, or to be provided on a unit price-based pricing basis.
In addition, both bitter and MSUA recognize the actual number of units, to be provided
by bitter or currently only an estimate.
As a result, the agreement between MSUA and bitter will contain specific language to confirm
that the total scope of the project to be provided by the bitter on a unit pricing basis
may increase or decrease in the sole discretion of MSUA.
I'll just take off the hand as a dairy.
So this is the start of our fiber unit.
recently improved to get the design. We have the design. We put it up for bid. This is an
obviously all of the fiber project, but I mean this is like the main stuff to get rolling.
So the first one is for the actual material. And so we say unit prices because you know
they're bidding. Every widget that we think we're going to need on this project they bid it.
So, and then we talk about the language is a little bit long. Because we talk about you know
funding. So here at the next meeting we are going to bring before you like our loan for the actual
fiber construction in the AMI. So, you know something with falter or whatever. I don't see that
being a problem. We've got to people reach out to us with some questions about you know they're
going to bid on the funding. So that seems to be good. So I would like to say that I appreciate all
your hard work in that. I've been a lot of meetings, a lot of long meetings to get us to this point.
It's been a long time getting here. I'm excited. I know we've probably been working on getting fiber in
my AMI for at least three years. And we're finally to the point that a year from now. Everybody
will have fiber. And it's a really cool thing that we'll be able to start with the city and it'll be a
good revenue generator for the city that's going to be needed long term. But the work that's
staff, but I don't know this, I can make you all because I know it's been a lot, but thank you for getting
this finally to this point. We're working out. I mean we've just arrived with the Mercedes and we've
been a lot of people work on it. I mean I want to thank everybody that we've had help along the way.
I mean municipal cities like Phonka, Salas, El Reno to co-op local culture around here that's that
hey we're in the fiber businesses of what we do. I mean we had a really good meeting today with a co-op
and they talked about hey if you need help we would happy to like obviously with sport fees but they
would do a call center. You know like we're if you have an issue then kind of let's get off the ground
like hey and issue with the fiber they can do a call center. Like Lincoln did their call center
in the beginning. So yeah they have like a lot of a lot of people and they've just got a
profit the map because they said you know so many of the things you can just solve like a turn
you're round or off turn it back on you know I mean just stuff like that. They dispatch for 30 some
co-op. Salas, Salas, Palma was amazing. Yeah. Yeah. When we went up there in two
in the coming now I saw the Ponka city city manager like a three months ago and he said you know
he said you kind of like they jumped it's going to be the next city manager. He was like it's it was a
big headache but he said I don't think that I can express the value for economic development that it
brings for a community like even if it breaks even you know the product we get to our customers and then
the kind of it is like huge. And you know we've we've tried to get true fiber here true high speed
broadband internet here and it's really been a tour trying to get someone else to come in. We've had a
couple of fiber nights come in want to do it.
They seem kind of sketched and just not someone we want to do business with and it may not have been in the case
I may not have been that but it felt that way to us and we think it just kept putting us in the direction that we need to do ourselves and
I can't say enough about what these guys have done on this project because they got a lot of stuff going on to that
I'll come back with this or any of my leaders
They've been in a lot of work on a lot of different projects
So a lot of the services where we're offering now are getting ready to change dramatically for our citizens for the better
And that's because we have forward thinkers and all these positions that are willing to put in the work in the time and the dedication to get it done
So again, thank you all for your work
And this is the board of the I mean there could be somebody else that comes in we get pervading anybody from coming out
You know what that's just like nobody's given to this point. So it's a
motion to smooth
Do we have to read this whole action? Sorry
It's not usually in here like this. So that's why I'm asking okay, I'm just making sure because again
It doesn't usually have it in the action that way so sometimes it's specific and we have to read it at all
five
H
award bid to Benton
preage LLC for the MS UA
185 that's eight six five of construction services project not throughout the trust manager to negotiate contract
Consistent with the bid documents and contingent upon legal review and confirmation of funding available
availability both bitter and MSUA recognized that many of the units be provided under bid and agreement between bitter and MSUA
Provided on a unit pricing basis
In addition both bitter and MSUA recognize the actual number of units be provided by bid and are currently only an estimate as a result
The agreement between MSUA bid or voting tanks specific language to confirm the total scope of the project to be provided by bid or on a unit pricing basis may increase or decrease
decrease in the sole discretion of MSUA
So this is the construction portion the one that you just did was in the channel
So it'd be the everything out the fiber itself the bolts that nodes on the pole a little bit this right here is the
contractor that will actually install the fiber for us and I do know the Tyler Stone
He's called around about this
contractor and her really good reviews from other communities they put in
Really no complaints on how they've done it and pretty excited about having these guys
Do this for an our community they actually give us a lot of tips too. I mean you know because we'll have to come back and do dropped all the houses and they kind of give us some good tips on how to get
Thank you, Mr. President.
Thank you.
All right.
Five-high.
Award-minute to Newcome.
Is that correct?
Newcome.
Solutions.
MSU-A25-87-Fiber-Node.
Shelter project.
In the amount.
Not to exceed five hundred and sixty nine thousand three hundred nine nine
dollars.
And authorized to trust management.
Execute to contract with Newcome.
Solutions.
And confirmation of funding availability.
The award includes a base project cost of five hundred twenty thousand one hundred
fifty dollars.
Which provides for the construction and installation of a new fiber-node shelter, including a project
contingency.
The bid award also includes the acceptance of the following additional options.
Fire suppression system.
Eight hundred sixty three dollars.
An exterior, ground rain.
Eight thousand three hundred eighty six dollars.
So this will be the control house concrete building that is sitting where the fiber or where
where our fiber is coming.
Just give the trend.
Where location right now would be down an off-center.
It'll have the racks and this is the world house.
All the equipment.
It's not the bid that's not here today before you.
It'll house all the equipment there.
We have a main hub for where the fiber comes in where we distribute it out of.
That's what the facility here is.
And this everything is at the project is super successful.
I mean they will have to build them at the well-timing other ones somewhere.
But that would be a problem to have.
You got to start somewhere.
So just so you know, maybe in the business for twenty seven years before retiring right
in the penetration rate in some of these communities like Pompaciti.
They were at forty percent.
And that's what we heard ourselves on to is about forty percent.
I think it'll be much higher here.
I think we'll be up in the sixty percent range on the penetration rate because we don't have any
competitors here.
We don't have a good fiber in that work here.
And I know the goal for everybody here is to make it affordable.
We don't want to make it to where people can afford to have it.
So I believe our penetration rate will be much higher.
I'm right from the work go and which is exciting because people need it.
Kids from school need it.
and it just hadn't been provided here for so long.
People are actually leaving a two-year-old question.
Yeah, AT&T is pulling out of Miami,
except for cellular service in November of this year.
So that'll just leave Spark Life is your only option
for Internet service.
Before I became mayor, I know they try to get both,
come in to Miami, and both one and nothing new
is that we've talked to them a couple of times,
they still want nothing to do with it.
So again, the point we really have to do it
or go with someone we really didn't trust.
And so that's why we decided to do ourselves.
In this good package, it shows options
for building a new versus refurbing.
Why did we choose the new versus refurbing?
Just as we can pick exactly how it's laid out.
So if you buy a refurbished one,
the inside may be set up differently.
That one, the doors are at where the racks are at,
different things like that.
And it was like a month longer to get a brand new one.
So you could be generations into, you know,
where the previous fiber ran into it,
and it was like, okay, well, you don't have all your electronics
setting up there that have a whole building,
is there anything else there you can come in?
That's the big thing is you can actually design
how you want whatever you go to get one, they'll tell them
about what they want, and they go see what they can find
out there, and then they redo them.
There are three more pieces, at least for more pieces,
if you guys have saved before you, before you don't,
so you don't think that there's the equipment
that will go in the shelters, so this doesn't include that,
the equipment that's in that shelter
in some of the other stuff, and then the service drops,
and then there's the cost to get the fiber to us.
So those are the three main things that,
which we're currently talking
in a different bin there, right now,
about providing as you know, fiber to the city.
Yeah, they're right there, there was just reviewing
what that equipment was that we put in here,
before they actually had an order that bit to that,
just make sure we cut exactly where we wanted.
That's why you don't have it before you today.
Motion to approve.
Second.
All right.
Each step, all right.
Jones, Jones.
All right.
Thank you.
This is a huge deal.
Big.
5J resolution, MSU-82026904,
establishing a 10% late payment fee
for on all non-utility services, providing for administration,
and enforcement, providing severability, and establishing
an effective date.
Miss me.
So whenever it says, providing for a measure, and for what, so what kind of non-utility services kind of like tipping fees, like there's a few restaurants we have that, you know, go out there and they jump and then they charge it.
Well, in the past we can never charge them on like the, you kind of felt like some people use as long as it's like their personal bank, you know, so it's like we're doing this.
So it's like okay, if you don't want to pay that's fine, that you're not paying 10% like the on top.
It's just like any other service you use in your personal life.
What's the mother's name?
Well, it's a living piece.
A real agreement.
Yeah, a real agreement.
Yeah.
A real agreement.
So that's okay.
Hi.
Sorry to any anybody has me catching me Sonnellen.
You want to see it on sex with you?
Yeah.
So if you make him work with anything catching his clusters, I don't want to be looking out on buttons.
You know, we want something to catch you for the name.
Yeah.
I'm telling your friend goes or start getting a role on email.
My friends.
Because obviously, the more so advocacy, the more dessas things we had, the more successful one.
That's 10 day.
I'm just telling you, I think you take the lot of counts.
Remember when you go first.
Hello.
Hi.
I mean, I don't have a background before that.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Yes, sir.
All right.
Over 10.
This meeting will be continued from council chambers,
Reconvenient the staff room for purposes of executive section
of the completion of agenda item number 10
of the regular city council meeting.